Finding Aid for Lee E. Landes papers, 1983-1987
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Lee E. Landes papers 1983-1987
Landes, Lee E. (Lee Everett)
0.6 linear feet
2010065 Aa 2
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Collection received from Lee Landes in November, 2009 (donor no. 10288 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Lee E. Landes and his wife Sue founded Mothers Against Drunk Driving (MADD) of southeast Michigan in 1982, after losing their son in "an alcohol related accident" (Argus-Press, Owosso, Michigan, 9/15/82). Landes served as spokesman for the local chapter of MADD and then as Michigan State Director of MADD in the mid 1980s.
The Landes collection includes organizational records, correspondence, promotional materials, and legal records of the national board, as well as materials from the Michigan and Texas chapters.
Subjects:
Drunk driving--Michigan.; Drunk driving--United States.; Drunk driving--Prevention.; Landes, Lee E. (Lee Everett).; Lightner, Candy.; Mothers Against Drunk Driving (Organization)
- Organizational records
  - National board
    - General, 1983-1986, 4 folders (Box 1)
    - Board meeting (firing of Candy Lightner), September 11, 1985 (Box 1)
    - Tax exempt status, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Internal matters, 1985-1986, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Report, "Mothers Against Drunk Driving in 1986 Problems and Recommendations," by Anna Marie Sant'Anna and Robert S. Weiss (Box 1)
    - Keywell and Rosenfeld, legal council 1986-1987, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - National Council of Chapters Affairs (NCCA)
    - General, 1985-1986, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Memorandum, September 12, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Michigan chapter, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Houston chapter, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clippings and pamphlets (Box 1)